ERIK KIMSEY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / CREATIVE TECHNOLOGIST

T: 540 278 4525 E: kimseyerik@gmail.com www.erikkimsey.com

linkedin.com/in/erikkimsey | behance.net/kimseyerik | qithub.com/erikkimsey

SKILLS

Full-Stack Web Development

- JavaScript, React, Angular,
- CSS3, Less, Sass,
- P5.js, GreenSock, JQuery, D3
- HTML5, Bootstrap,
- NodeJS, Express, Apollo, Axios,
- SQLite3/SQL, and a bit of...
- ...GraphQL, Redis, NextJS.

Languages

- Javascript,
- Python,
- C/C++.
- Java (Android)
- Processing

Design

- Adobe Illustrator,
- Photoshop,
- InDesign,

EDUCATION

2018 - 2019 COMPUTER SCIENCE

Lambda School

Curriculum:

https://lambdaschool.com/courses/cs/

2006 - 2010 **PHILOSOPHY**

James Madison University Minors: writing & design

STATEMENT

Tenacious, creative software developer. Specializing in web-application and mobile-web development.

Professional experience as a developer and 4 years in the software industry. Computer Science education from Lambda School and Bachelor's Degree in Philosophy from James Madison University.

EXPERIENCE

2018

NEXTLEVELSH!T (GERMANY) Front-End Developer (Contract)

In collaboration with NEXTLEVEL, I contributed to developing and debugging an interactive guilloche, using Angular 4 & D3.

2012 - 2016

ROSETTA STONE

Studio Recording Technician/ **Product Support Agent**

Monitored and recored Rosetta Stone Studio coaching sessions. Coordinated with various departments regarding monitoring various sessions. Provided technical support and troubleshooting.

2016 - 2017

CHARTIQ

JavaScript Developer

Helped implement ProCharts into a client's (eToro) AngularJS application. Helped build and debug aspects of ChartIQ's flagship JavaScript/HTML5 charting solution. Contributed to public-facing documentation.

MY FAVORITE PROJECTS

D3 / Angular Guilloche

https://www.npmjs.com/package/nls-guilloche

Conway's Game of Life

https://ek-game-of-life.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/ErikKimsey/Conways-Life